Hey everyone, how's it going?  Today I'm going to
do something a little different.   Tell me
what you think of
this format, but today I'm going to do something
that's part of our daily routine
when we're creating perfumes, which
is doing the famous dilutions, right?  So
today I'm here with some materials.  I
'm with Lebanon from India, from Laso, I'm
with uh Juniper Berry, Juniper, right, which
is also known as Juniper.  I'm here
with Ilang, completely, completely Ilang.
Uh, I also have some hydro
beta ionone on hand.  I'm also using Hydro Nona Beta
and this Grapefruit Divical, which, judging by the
smell,
I think is very promising. I'm really
excited to try this one too,
Rapeuitivo, a grapefruit base from
Givico.
So, I'm going to dilute it along with you all,
I'll show you from the beginning how
my process works to perform
these dilutions, okay?  So, well, what do
I do first, right?
First, we need to
select which container we're going to use; in my
case, I use
amba glass bottles with droppers.
So, we have five materials here, but
I'm reusing
an old bottle, okay?  So, I just
need four new bottles, okay?
So, I'm going to take this out,
I'm going to separate the four bottles,
okay?   I
'll keep the rest.
So, we have all four.  Now we
also need to assemble
the pipette part here.
So let's open it.
So, look, we're separating four here.
We have the bulb, we have the cap, and now we have the
pipettes, four glass pipettes, and the
bottles.
And there's one more important thing:
these polexan discs
help prevent evaporation
in dropper bottles.  So it's
really important to use this.  So
we start here by fitting the bulb
until it locks into place.
We add
the glass pipette.  Actually, this one
looks a bit irregular, but I do
n't think there will be a problem.   Be
careful not to break it.
Beauty?
And the polexan disc,
it will fit.  You have to remove the middle part,
right?  And it fits in here.
And then we can close it up and
even use a little bit of force.
Ready.  And so we have a... a
closed, sealed bottle.  And then we
can
unlock it here, see?
Sometimes it's a little difficult
for me to remove the seal; I have to use a bit of
force
.
Unfortunately, some suppliers of
these bottles sometimes use materials that
are too hard, making
this process difficult.  Okay, it's
done now.  So, I usually do that
beforehand.  Yeah, and I'm going to do that to everything
here now.  Okay, now that we've made
all the bottles here, the next step will be to
write it down.  I like to write
labels in this style.  So, I
put the chemist's name and the
dilution percentage.  And I use a small ball of
some color to indicate the
olfactory family.  Well, just in a
general way, right?  So, it can be white
if it's musca or if it's something sweet.
Well, it can be black if it's woody or
animalic.  So, for each family of
active children, I have a small
colored label to help with this
separation.  So, before we get to the
percentage, I'm showing
you the spreadsheet I use to
record my dilutions.  Well, in the
spreadsheet I like to record the name of the
subject matter.  I also include
the price, or the price
I can pay if I want to
buy in larger quantities to
produce a batch of perfume.  And that's it, and I'll
put the quantity in grams.  And that
helps me get an idea of ​​the price per gram
of each material.  Later on, I'll
use this in some Excel formulas
to figure out how much
that fragrance I'm trying to
create will cost, okay?  So this is very
important when it comes to knowing the
final cost of the fragrance.  So I'll
add this to my
perfume database here.
Well, you can see here in column J, I
put the standard dilution, which would be the
recommended dilution for this material,
this raw material.  So how do I
find that out?  Well, I can see it on the
perfume website, you know, on Márcio's site,
that he puts the recommended dilution.
Sometimes I also look at The Good
Centy, which is a website that has a
series of databases about
raw materials, including
dilution recommendations.
Yeah, and sometimes I also see
people asking in the group, you know, who have already used
this material, to see if it's strong
or not.  And then I'll start adding it.  When I'm
really not sure, I guess, or I start
with 10% and then, if it's too strong,
I dilute it to 1%.  Okay?
Oh, another point, I know that my
30 ml bottles here can
hold about 24 g of
final solution, okay?  De eh matériapra
diluizada já no álcool.  So, 24g fits in
here.  In other words, I will always use 24 g
as a base to dilute and
calculate how many grams of each ingredient I will need
.
So I have this other column which is "
diluted grams," "grams to be diluted," right?
Which is precisely how many grams of the
raw material I'm going to use.  And I
basically multiply the 10%, which would be
the dilution, by 24. And then I have
the amount of material
I'm going to use it for.  So now we're going to make
the labels here, right?  So we're going to have
the grapefíico.
In this case, I'll just put
10% here directly.
Instead of making two labels to
save on labeling.
And I'll have to get another one of these.  And
I buy it here on Amazon, so it's
very cheap, very easy for me to buy
it here.
And now I just put it here.  There's not
much mystery to it.  Actually,
I like doing something simple
that won't require much effort on a
daily basis, you know?  So, sometimes we
start to overcomplicate
things, and then when we go to do them, we
get lazy, we don't
want to, right?  Yeah, get things done.  So
I end up trying my best to simplify
my life here.  Now I realize I
put it wrong here.  It wasn't supposed to be
used here; it was supposed to be put in this one
since it already has frankincense.  So I'll have to
make another one and put it on top.
Ready.  Lebanon from India, 10%.   So
what do I have to do now?
When the bottles arrive, I don't have
much faith in their hygiene, you know?  Theoretically,
they shouldn't contain any
residue inside, but I personally don't
trust them.  So I always grab some
lower-quality alcohol that I have here,
which I don't want to use for perfume.
So, I'm transferring the alcohol from one
bottle to another, just to...
just to do a
basic cleaning of the perfume,
or rather, the bottle, right?
And I also take advantage of this step with the
alcohol to do a
little sanitization of the beaker that
I might use, right?  Yeah, at
some point, right?  I'm going to leave the
frankincense for last, because the frankincense is
still a bit dirty, so to speak,
from the frankincense solution that was previously in
this bottle.  But basically, this is what I
do.
A very good technique, I don't know if you'll be able
to see it on camera, but a
good technique to avoid spilling is to
use this pipe here as a guide
for the alcohol that will flow down, and it
follows the path.
And that helps prevent alcohol from spilling
, okay?  This is very interesting so
we don't waste a single drop of
alcohol in the perfume.  I put in too much, I'll
try to take some out here.
Well, so I always do this process, I
put the alcohol in, shake it,
I let the alcohol really
go all the way around the area, the bulb
too, right?  I turn it around so the alcohol
comes here to the bottle, I shake it,
and
then I come and change it for the
next one, right?  I'm going to take this away now
and take the alcohol
to the next person.  And I follow that process.
Little by little we'll be sanitizing
everything to remove any small residues that
might be inside the bottles.
Still, sometimes it slips up, but it's okay
, it just happens.   It's
always good to have a piece of paper handy, right?
always important
to avoid this.  We can also
keep using the same glass bottle here
to
refill it with
alcohol after it's been washed.
And it's interesting in this process because
you start to see that there were residues
inside, you start to be able to see in the
alcohol that comes out that it was really
worth doing this process because you
manage to remove impurities and you see that
the impurities were really there.
Even though you can't see it, sometimes it's so
small, but it
helps, it prevents problems.
Ready.  So this is the
sanitization part, and all of this was just to
prepare our environment, prepare the
bottles as well, see what the dilution will be
, and label them.  And now, after
all this, I'm finally going to
dilute the raw materials, being very
careful not to mix them up or add
the wrong amount.
So, first of all, I'll leave a
glass jar.  I like using glass.
I like to use glass in these situations
precisely because glass
interacts less with plastic.
And although, you know, the alcohol comes
in a plastic container, so I don't
know if it really makes that much of a difference
, but then I come here
and put in about 50 ml.
This is a slightly better quality alcohol.
He has some stamps and stuff.  I think it's
an alcohol of a slightly
higher quality.
And here I bring my
disposable pipettes.
I usually leave a napkin or
something to help open it.   So
what do you all think now?  We're just
getting started.  There's one more step
before that, which is precisely to put the
BHT in each one here, uh, in each of these
vials, okay?  So, what do I do?  I
put 24 mg of BHT in each vial
because, considering I'll have 24 g
of solution, it's basically 1 g per 1 L,
so to speak, more or less.  Well,
since I'm not going to measure it in liters, I'll measure it
in grams. I use 1 g of BHT for
every, let's say, 1 kg, right?  Or would it be
1 g for every 1 mg per gram of
solution, right?  Therefore, 24 g of
solution, 24 mg of BHT, is needed to have
that antioxidant effect in the solution.
So, first we put the vial in,
we tar it.  It's interesting to use
this protection because it will prevent
wind from coming in, blowing it, and causing it to
change too much, because it's very
sensitive, right?  So any air that
passes through can cause changes here.  You can see
that it keeps changing, it keeps
altering the decimal places.  So
ideally, we should leave it with some kind of
protection to avoid that, okay?  And then I'll go there
and put the BHT here.
Yeah, it's tricky because I put the camera over here
, the webcam, and sometimes
my hand will block your view.   Damn it
.  How do I do this
now, huh?
Good.  I think I've found a position here where
you'll be able to see, but I'll be
very careful spilling the
grains, right?  It's like BHT crystals
until I reach 24 mg.  Very
carefully, right?
so as not to overtake.  So, look, it's already
23. What am I going to do?  I'll
leave it like this, right?  23, 24, 25. So, I
'll leave it at that, no need to overdo it.
And then I'm going to repeat this process with
all the bottles.
Remember to always tare
the bottle whenever you change it.
Another one that's done here, it
doesn't need to be 100% perfect.  It's
ready,
now we can start putting
the ingredients inside.  As you can
see, there are several small steps involved in ensuring
your dilution is safe,
accurate, and with minimal risk of
contamination.
Let's start then with the hydrobeta
ionone.   The
first step we need to
take here is to remove this stopper that's
coming up here.   At
times like these, it's very useful to have
slightly longer nails,
but that's not going to happen today.
So, grab a brand
new pipette, okay?  And now we're going to retrieve
2.4 g of this material.
Oh, it's almost here.  I think just
one more drop made it
2.4.
Now that we have 2.4, we
just need to complete it until we reach the mark.  I'm
not going to tarp now.  I'll
leave it as it is and I'll top it up with
alcohol until it reaches
24g.  Beauty?  So it's 2.4 g.  I'll keep
completing it until I reach 24.
All done.  It was just a little bit over, but it's
okay.   Okay, so
now I'm going to seal it off
with 10% hydrobenone.  I can give it a
basic mix, but there's no problem with
that; there's no need to mix it
because it will be left to rest, so
it will dissolve easily in a day. There's not
much to stress about.
And now we're going to move on to the next one, which will be
grapefruit.
So let's do the same process.   I'll
put it here,
I'll try to position it better
so you can see it and I can see it too, so
I can be in an OK position.
Remember to
throw the pipette away after each use.  So, unless
you've been in the hobby for a while, if you
want to try, uh, tying a pipette like this
, if you know what you're
doing, that's fine.  But if you don't know,
if you're just starting out, I don't
recommend reusing pipettes at all
, okay?  If you're just starting out
, use a disposable pipette, throw it
away as soon as you use it, and never, ever,
under any circumstances,
reuse a pipette from one subject
to another, okay?  So don't do that
because you'll contaminate your
materials.
Sometimes it goes over a little, and if it's
less than 10%,
for example, 2.4 g, even if it were up to
200 g, 200 mg more, no, there's no
problem, okay?  It won't make a
big enough difference
to ruin everything for you.  So
relax, but whenever possible try to be as
accurate as you
can.
And now we're going to bring it up to 2.4, or rather,
up to 24 g with alcohol.
Yeah, it went a little over too, but that's okay
.
It's worth it, a little bit of alcohol went over the top,
compensating for the fact that a little bit of the
chemical went over.  The important thing is that it stays there,
mostly close to 10%.   Okay
?  Okay, then.  Graproit divical
tá aqui.
Now, for the complete ilang, I'm not going to do it
at 10%, I'm going to do it at 1%.  So,
instead of 2.4 g, it will only be
240 mg, okay?  So now I'm
really going to have to be more careful,
because I only have 240 mg of lang here
to inject, okay?  So,
the thing is, now there's a
pipette here, right?  A drip irrigation system, then, is a
slightly more complex job,
okay?  I'm generally not a big fan of
using the dropper because it's
a bit difficult to dose.  But let's
see if this works out.  Let's
see if I can get the dosage exactly the way
I'd like it.
Oh, he's already falling.
This one is actually easier to
dose.  I don't know exactly why, but he's
falling quite calmly.
Ready.
And now I'm going to
complete it up to 24g again.
The alcohol is gone.  Let's hurry and
add more before it goes out,
before the scale goes out.
Good, that's settled.
He's at 1%, but he's become very, very
opaque.  Can you see this?  I don't know if you can
see it here, look.  It's very
opaque.
It's not translucent, is it?  I don't know
if, when I dilute it, when I wait a
little while, uh, one day like that, it will
dilute better.  But right now it's
very, very opaque, and that's only at 1%, right?
Let me see how it's going. I
only smell alcohol.  I only just now smelled alcohol.   It worked out
very well, didn't it?
Good.  So, this one was the most
difficult, so to speak.  Let's move on to
juniper now.  Okay, we have the juniper here
from the perfumer,
and we're now going to add 2.4g of
juniper, which is also known as
zimbro.
Good.  This time it was a little less,
but it's okay.  It's even better
so that it's not difficult, right, to do this
dosage.  And now we'll add up
to 24g.
The alcohol is gone.  We'll run as
usual.
And that's the saga, my friends.  That's the
saga.  from a perfumer who wants to
learn things at home.
Ready.  The juniper tree also turned,
apparently it also became quite
opaque, right?  It's quite milky, but as I
said, it might dilute better after a day
.  And now let's talk about
frankincense from India, from Lasagonian Peninsula, huh?  This is
the first article about Las that I
have, and I'm going to tell you.   I've
tried it on my skin, pure and simple, and it's very,
very good.  It's a very
different subject like that.  It's a
unique scent, completely unique, and very good,
actually.
So, let's look at this, which is basically
2.4g, so let's make it 10%.
Frankincense from India,
as you can see, is slower to set.
Each material has a different viscosity,
so not all materials set
quickly; some set slowly, and
we have to learn to do it
carefully so as not to overdo it, right?   It's
almost passing by here already.
Well, I'll stop here so as
not to risk putting too much.
And now we're going to
24 g.  Fill here up to 24 g.
Perfect.  24 g.  We're closed.
And now, uh, take scent strips and
drip them onto the scent strip and take the opportunity
to get to know new raw materials.
Let's explore, let's take advantage of the fact that we're
already here, and I'll take a quick look around and come
back to show you what
I thought of these raw materials.
Okay, folks, so I usually grab
the scent strips here and
fold them all together, right?  I like
to fold the olfactory tapes because I
don't have that clip to
hold the tape in place, okay?  So, when I
wet it, I put it on the table.
So, if I don't do it, if I don't fold it,
the tape will touch the table and
contaminate the table with the smell of the tape, and
contaminate the tape with something else that
might be on the table.  So, if the table,
for example, is already contaminated with, I don't know
, some kind of powder that sometimes
contaminates, like ambroxan, we'll see that it fell on the
table, so if it gets on the tape it will
interfere with the evaluation, okay?  So, I
always do this, and I
avoid putting the strip directly into the
bottle because there might be
something on the strip that could contaminate
my solution.  So, what do I like
to do?  I use the pipette specifically
to pipette here
without touching it, and that way I can assess the situation and
reduce the risk of any kind of
cross-contamination.
Beauty?  So this is how I do it.
Let's start now with the
Indian Libano,
terpenic, citrusy,
a little spicy, very
perishable
and certainly very bright, okay?  So the
resinous nuance here is minimal.
What really stands out and shines through is
this citrusy quality, this very
citrusy, slightly bitter quality, it
even reminds you of something like lemon.
So, very good Alibaba from India.
Now let's look at
the juniper tree.
Well, the juniper is a little different
from what I expected; it
's not as bright as I thought.  It's
spicy, bitter, has a
slightly woody quality, and a
light spiciness in the
background,
but it's a fresh spice, right?  It's not
a hot spice like pepper,
but it's more of a
woody spice; it's not a sweet spice,
right?  For example, card daam is a
slightly sweeter spice,
as it is a somewhat
calmer and woodier spice.
And maybe with something
a little balsamic, I don't know.
Well, here we have the complete Ilang,
and it's a
very interesting scent.  It has that
sunny side, it
has a jasmine side, right?  That
benzyl salicylate thing,
that thing that leans towards jasmine
too,
but it has the fruity nuance of ylang-ylang.
So very, very good, very complex as
well.
Hydrobeta ionone
has something very similar to
nimetone,
but it brings something a little
rounder, a little more velvety, a
little more woody than aimone, which
to me isn't very woody.
Here we start to pick up a
slightly more woody nuance,
and there's that slightly
powdery side, it has a slightly uh
pulvery quality, but it's very well balanced, a really
nice material.
And finally, Grapefruit Divico,
Givoldan's grapefruit-based drink.
And this material is really good, man.  Very
good.  A very bright, slightly bitter note of grapefruit
.
Wow, very good.  Very realistic as well.
There's something even more sour.  This material is very good
.  Oh dear.
And that's it, folks.  So, thank you to
everyone who followed along this far, and I'll see you in the
next video.